我们希望能进入神殿并获得尊敬
We wish to sit in the temple and win respect.
我相信以后 你们会记住我的慷慨大方
I trust you will remember my generosity in the days to come.
代表我供万人瞻仰
My likeness in the temple for all to see.
对抗这可憎之物 保卫他的神殿!
Defend his temple against this abomination!
我们点起了一团火 将会把罗马烧成灰烬
We are lighting a fire that will burn Rome to cinders.
去找彼拉多
Go to Pilate.
- 把这座城市从罗马人的屠杀中拯救出来  - 绝不!
- Save this city from a Roman massacre.  - Never!
狂热分子和埃塞俄比亚人结盟了
The zealots have formed an alliance with Ethiopia.
计划发动一场巨大的暴动
They plan to launch a huge uprising against Rome.
走开!
Move aside!
我们被出卖了 快拿!
We are betrayed. Quick!
别管埃塞俄比亚的武器了 我们自己还有
Forget the Ethiopians' weapons. We still have our own.
约亚拿 跟我来
Joanna, come with me.
她会被处死 克劳迪娅
She will be put to death, Claudia.
哥尼流 行刑
Cornelius, begin.
就到此为止吧
This ends here.
本片涉及圣经内容的名词 段落 均参照和合本翻译
公元: 圣经续 第一季第12集
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hdscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 影子
翻译: 飘飘行天下 猫呗 鸟生鱼汤
约翰 怎么了?
John, what is it?
翻译: 舒大卷子 喵喵 波特妹子
雕像
The statue.
校对: 飘飘行天下 影子
大帝的雕像
The statue of the Emperor.
送来了
It's here.
好吧 现在...
Well, now...
它就在这了
Here it is.
你想怎样?
What do you want?
等我下了命令
When I decree it,
就把雕像护送进神殿
the statue will be escorted to the temple.
就安放在妇人院内
There it shall be placed in the Court of the Women,
除非我有新的命令 否则将一直放在那里
and there it shall remain until I tell you otherwise.
巡抚...
Governor...
唯一不确定的只是死亡人数
The only uncertainty regards the number of deaths.
这就取决于你的作用了
And that's where you become useful.
我们帮不了你
We cannot help you.
我还以为我们是朋友呢
And I thought we were friends.
你的妻子和我是朋友 对吧?
Your wife and I are friends. Aren't we?
你知不知道你的妻子...
Do you know that your wife...
他在胡说八道
He's lying.
你的妻子...
Your wife...
来找我
came to me
揭发了埃塞俄比亚和狂热分子
and helped me expose a conspiracy
勾结的阴谋?
between Ethiopia and the zealots?
这是我们之间的小秘密
It's our little secret.
我对你感激不尽
And I am in your debt.
不过看她刚才的样子...
But her outburst just now...
倒让我怀疑
makes me wonder.
你是不是毫不知情?
Were you not aware of this?
也许我压根不欠你人情
Maybe I owe you nothing after all.
我妻子...
My wife...
向你报信这事我知情而且允许了
delivered this information with my knowledge and approval.
但我本人和她的所作所为毫无关系
But I myself am untainted by her actions,
所以你不用谢我
so there is no debt.
不过同时你也没有任何方法
But you also have no means
可以胁迫我 或者胁迫神殿
by which to blackmail me or the temple,
我看这就是你今天叫我来的
which seems to me to be the true purpose
主要目的吧
of our conversation today.
你在这没有同盟 你贿赂不了谁也欺凌不了谁
You have no allies here, no one to bribe or bully.
这雕像绝对不可能进入神殿一步
And the statue will never, ever enter the temple.
想得挺美
So you say.
但到时候我的军队一开进
But when it comes to it and my men march toward you,
你还有什么能耐?
how will you stop us?
我们得离开耶路撒冷
We need to get out of Jerusalem.
你为什么要放弃神殿?
Why would you abandon the temple?
因为耶稣已经警告过我们
Because Jesus warned us.
"这都是灾难的起头"
"These are the beginnings of sorrows."
到时候神殿一片瓦
Won't be a single stone of the temple
也剩不下 西门
left standing, Simon.
记得他怎么跟我们说的
Remember what he told us.
"多处必有地震 饥荒"
"There will be earthquakes and famine and troubles."
所以我们该收拾一下去山里
So we should pack up and go to the hills.
没错 就这么做
Yes. Let's do that.
罗马人要让耶路撒冷去朝拜一个假神像
The Romans are about to make Jerusalem worship a false idol.
这已经不再是我们的斗争了
It's not our fight... not anymore.
谁来了?
Who was that?
大祭司派来的信使
A messenger from the high priest.
说什么了?
Saying what?
只说他想见我
Just that he wants to see me.
恰好在雕像来的这天?
On the same day that the statue arrives?
他想让我们为他而战
He wants us to fight for him.
有何不可?
And why wouldn't we?
因为他们会把我们撕成碎片
Because they will cut us to pieces.
他说要给我们圣殿的时候 我们干嘛相信他?
Why did we believe him when he offered us sanctuary?
他总是在找机会利用我们
He was always just waiting for a chance to use us.
也许不一定
We don't know that.
一切尚未可知
Not yet.
奉基督的名 我饶恕你
In the name of Christ, I forgive you.
哥尼流...
Cornelius...
神慈悲你的悲伤与悔改
God has looked kindly on your sorrow and repentance.
打发人往约帕去 请彼得来
Send men to Joppa and find a man called Peter,
他住在海边一个硝皮匠西门的家里
who is staying with Simon the Tanner, near the sea.
彼得
Peter.
这些都被视为不洁
These are looked upon as unclean.
神所洁净的 你不可当作俗物
But do not call anything impure that God has cleansed.
有三个人来找你
There are three men downstairs.
他们在楼下
They have come for you.
起来 下去 和他们同往
Go with them.
不要疑惑 因为是我差他们来的
Don't be afraid, because I have sent them.
彼得
Peter.
有人在楼下
There are men downstairs.
你笑什么?
Why are you smiling?
你是彼得
You're Peter.
是的
I am.
我见到了...
I had a...
我不... 我不知道该怎么说...
I'm not... I'm not sure what I should call it...
那不是梦
Not a dream.
我很清醒 但是...
I was awake, but...
我来这里是...
I was visited...
有人派我...
by...
我不知该如何称呼他
an I know not what.
那是天使
An angel.
然后... 我听到了你的名字
And... and I heard your name.
我曾目睹和参与了许多恶行
I have been a witness and party to many terrible deeds.
我看着耶稣死了
I saw your Jesus die.
而这双手也...
And these hands have...
我的理智...
My mind...
我的内心...
My heart...
都在呐喊"够了"
screams, "enough."
我的朋友约亚拿...
My friend Joanna...
她怎么样了?
How is she?
你杀了她
You killed her.
是吗?
Didn't you?
站起来
Stand up.
不要在我面前跪下
Don't kneel before me.
我也是人...
I'm just a man...
和你一样
like you.
谢谢你这么快来
Thank you for coming so swiftly.
因为是大祭司召唤...
Well, when the High Priest calls...
我在神殿那看到你一些兄弟
I've seen some of your brethren at the temple.
他们满心的喜悦让人感觉...
Their delight has been...
很温暖
heartwarming.
- 你知道雕像的事?  - 是的 当然
- You know about the statue?  - Yes, of course.
听着 我想集全城之力来对抗这个可憎之物
See, I am trying to unite the city against this abomination,
而且我相信 要是我们先把分歧放在一边
and I believe that if we all put our differences aside
团结一致 就一定能反抗暴行
and stand as one, then we can repel this barbarity.
这个想法很高尚
Well, that is certainly a noble intention.
但是 我们帮不上忙
But, um, we cannot help.
不好意思
I'm sorry.
我让你们回来
I let you back in.
我保障了你们的安全
I... I offered you safety.
那似乎是有条件的
With hidden conditions, it seems.
哦 这么说你们就不欠我人情了?
Oh, so suddenly you owe me nothing?
那神殿呢?
What about the temple?
在那个耶稣出现之前 你们难道不是把神殿
The building which, until this Jesus appeared,
看作宇宙的中心?
was the center of your universe?
- 你一点感觉都没有吗?  - 当然有
- Do you feel nothing for it?  - Of course I do.
但是现在我信仰耶稣
But I worship Jesus now.
我要拆散你的家庭
I will split you from your loved ones
我要把追随你们的人 还有他们的孩子
and will drive your followers and their children
都赶到荒野
into the wilderness.
我会打击你们 鞭打你们 用石头砸你们
I will beat and flog and stone you all.
谁也逃不了
No one will escape.
你这么快就改口威胁我了
How quickly you slip into threats.
看来他们对你的看法是对的
They were right about you after all.
不 不!
No. No!
我想拯救我们的城市!
I am trying to save our city!
而你们只关心自己!
But you have no interest in anything but yourselves!
滚出去
Get out.
滚出去!
Get out!
你觉得彼拉多察觉到了吗?
Do you think Pilate noticed?
我做了我该做的事
I did what I had to.
我觉得他看穿我了
I think he saw through me.
他发现我控制不了我妻子...
He realized that I have no control over my wife...
她当我的面说谎...
that she lies to my face...
总要有人来做决定
Someone had to make the decision.
背着我搞事
goes behind my back.
总要有人去做
It had to be done.
要是彼拉多把你做的事捅给那些狂热分子怎么办?!
What would happen if Pilate told the zealots what you did?!
他们会杀了我
They would kill me.
神殿会很危险
The temple would be endangered.
神殿啊 利亚!
The temple, Leah!
谁在乎你 在乎一个人 在乎一个家庭?
Who cares about you, about an individual, a family?
你比拿撒勒人好不到哪里去
You're no better than the Nazarenes.
我这么做是为我们好
I did it for us.
你这么做伤了我的心
And you broke my heart in the process.
回家去
Go home.
从现在开始你只能呆在那
From now on, you will stay there.
你以后就是我名义上的妻子
You are a wife to me in name only.
就是个称呼...
You're just a name...
一个影子
a shadow.
没有我 你根本当不上大祭司
Without me, you would never be High Priest.
- 没有我的家族...  - 别说了
- Without my family...  - Stop talking.
没人想听
No one's listening.
我需要知道神对我的旨意
I have to know God's plan for me.
他跟你说了什么?
What has he told you?
神说了什么?
What has God told me?
我不确定
I'm not sure.
我只是个渔夫
I'm just a fisherman.
但神授意我将他的道
But I've been commanded to preach his message
传遍世界的每个角落
to the ends of the earth,
而我现在看到你似乎也找到了
and now I see that you may also find the salvation
耶稣的救赎
that Jesus offers.
所以如果我一定要做点什么
So if I am to do this,
那我只能欢迎你 然后...
then I must welcome you and...
为你施洗
baptize you.
这就是我们来这的原因!
This is why we came!
这就是我们的使命!
This is our mission!
我还以为我女儿已经把我们忘了
There was me, thinking my daughter had forgotten us.
我向你道歉
I apologize.
我很担心我的丈夫
I'm worried about my husband.
我觉得他肩上的担子会...
I think the burden of his office has...
把他压垮
overwhelmed him.
他变得不可理喻 有时很暴力
He's become irrational, sometimes violent.
他的行为已经无法匹配
He no longer behaves in a way
大祭司的职位了
befitting the role of High Priest.
那你想让我做什么呢?
And what would you have me do about it?
神殿不再安全
Well, the temple is no longer safe.
需要你来稳住大局
It needs your stable influence.
你想让我们赶该亚法下台?
You want us to remove Caiaphas from office?
我觉得这对家族有利
I think it would be in our family's interest.
你可怜的丈夫对你的阴谋有一丝察觉吗?
Does your poor husband have any idea of what you're plotting?
怎么 难道你不想成为大祭司?
What, do you not want to become high priest?
利亚 他在联合整个民族
He is uniting the nation, Leah.
耶路撒冷甚至周边的每个教派都团聚在他四周
Every sect in Jerusalem and beyond has flocked to his side.
任何试图赶他下台的举动只会削弱我们的力量
Any attempt to remove him now would only weaken us all.
你害怕了
You're afraid.
住口
Stop it.
马上住口
Stop it now.
该亚法不能动
Caiaphas is untouchable.
除非他死了 不然没人能取代他
Only death can rob him of his position.
回去找你的丈夫
Go back to your husband.
这次没人能帮你
No one can help you with this.
她很危险...
She is dangerous...
已经失控了
Beyond control.
如果不小心 她会把我们都拖下水
And she'll drag us down if we're not careful.
那该拿她怎么办?
So what shall we do with her?
出去
Leave us.
我是犹太的巡抚
I am the Governor of Judea.
我肩负责任
I have responsibilities.
如果我抗命就会被杀
If I refuse to do this, I will be killed,
下一任会乐意去执行命令
and a new man will gleefully do it instead.
我也会失去你
And you'll be lost, too.
所以我别无选择!
So I have no choice!
你到底怎么了?
What is the matter with you?
你乐在其中
You enjoy it.
是因为那个女人吗?
Is this about that woman?
那个愚蠢的耶稣追随者?
That stupid Jesus follower?
她什么都不是
She was nothing.
就是个符号 是一时的愤怒...
A symbol, a moment of anger...
是提醒你必须对我忠诚
a reminder that you must remain loyal to me.
仅此而已
That's all.
这就是她全部的意义吗?
Is that all she was?
当然
Of course.
我不会再与你共进晚餐 看你洋洋自得
I will not dine with you and watch you gloat.
但你是我的妻子
But you are my wife.
你是我的妻子
You are my wife.
现在我孤身一人与他们为敌
Now, I am fighting them all on my own,
而且我会赢
and I am winning.
但我不能同时也与你为敌
But I cannot fight against you, too.
也许你不会每次都是赢家
Maybe you cannot win every battle.
是的 我会赢
Oh, yes, I can.
你要去精心准备我们的晚餐!
You will prepare our evening in exquisite detail!
还要像往常一样美艳动人
And you will look beautiful, as you always do.
我们在一起才会赢
And together we will win.
这就是我们的生活...
This is our life...
你的和我的...
Yours and mine...
在一起
together.
求你了 留下来多呆几天吧
Please, stay with us for a few more days.
我们都渴望听到更多耶稣的信息
We're all eager to hear more of Jesus' words.
我觉得这个小家伙不会让我走的
I don't think this little one will let me go.
我也不会让你走
I can't let you go, either.
我感觉如此鲜活 每寸皮肤都兴奋不已
I feel so alive. My skin prickles with it.
我... 我无法用语言表达
I... I wish I had the words.
我... 我内心充盈...
I'm... I feel full...
精神焕发 准备大干一番
full up, ready to burst.
百夫长
Centurion.
什么事?
What is it?
- 没关系 说吧  - 你需要回到耶路撒冷...
- No, you can speak.  - You are needed back in Jerusalem...
马上
urgently.
为何?
Because?
大帝的雕像到了
The statue of our emperor has arrived.
巡抚命令你
The Governor has ordered you
确保将它安全运往神殿
to ensure its safe passage to the temple.
谢谢你
Thank you.
呃...
Um...
我... 我必须回去了
I... I... I must go back.
我们也是
We must, too.
你不能这么做
You can't do it.
是的 我不能 但我是罗马人...
No, I can't, but I'm a Roman...
还是一个有命在身的士兵
and a soldier with orders.
你已经奉基督耶稣的名受洗了
You have been baptized in the name of Jesus Christ.
是的 但我仍是一名士兵
Yes, but I'm still a soldier.
那你会怎么做?
So what will you do?
我会...
I will...
我会祈求圣灵引导我
I will pray that the Holy Spirit will guide me.
预备!
Prepare yourselves!
开始!
Begin!
别走
Don't go.
你已经获得新生了
You have a new life now.
待会我会来找你们的
I'll come and find you afterwards.
抱歉这里发生的一切
I'm sorry for what has happened here.
我必须说出事实
I must speak the truth.
这事怪我
I am to blame for this.
我就知道
I knew it.
我不知道我当时在做什么
I didn't know what I was doing.
我以为我是在保护神殿 但...
I thought I was protecting the temple, but...
我的丈夫...
my husband...
他不顾你们死活
he doesn't care about you.
请原谅他
Please forgive him.
这么说我很伤心
It breaks my heart.
但背叛你们的人是我丈夫
But it was my husband who betrayed you.
他在找你
He's looking for you.
你家人怎么样?
How is your family?
他们很好 谢谢
They're well. Thank you.
你准备好履行你的职责了吗?
Are you ready to carry out your duties?
昨天有人引我去拿撒勒人的门徒那
I was led to the disciples of the Nazarene yesterday.
谁引你去的?
Led? By whom?
一位天使
An angel.
呃...
Uh...
是真的 我发誓
It's true. I swear.
就像梦一样 只不过我一直是清醒的
It was like a dream, except that I was always awake.
现在我理解了他们的信仰
And I understand their faith now.
我相信了
I believe.
你相信了?
You believe?
是的
Yes.
这么快?
So quickly?
他们的信仰很美
It's a beautiful thing.
可以成为我们的出路
And it could be our escape.
我觉得我丈夫失去了理智
I think my husband is losing his mind.
那就离开他
So leave him.
来追随这新的信仰
Come and follow this new faith.
来追随耶稣
Come and follow Jesus.
你要求太多
You ask a lot.
我需要考虑一下
I need to think.
无论何时你需要我 我都在
I'm here, whenever you need.
我以为他是真心实意的
I thought he was genuine.
我真以为我们有机会结束这...
I really thought we had a chance to end the...
- 我们出城吧  - 好极了
- Let's get out of the city.  - Great.
- 去山上等待耶稣归来  - 没错
- Go to the hills and wait for Jesus to return.  - Exactly.
没人动啊
No one's moving.
如果这不是耶稣归来的时刻呢?
What if this isn't the moment that Jesus comes back?
如果一切结束之后...
What if when it's all over,
没有地震 没有饥荒...
there are no troubles, no famine...
只有一座在它最需要我们的时候却被抛弃的神殿?
just a temple that we abandoned when it needed us most?
大祭司会来追杀我们
The high priest would come after us.
我们不能迫于害怕去做事
We can't act out of fear.
是的 我们必须凭良心做事
No. We must follow our conscience.
成千上万人会死去
Thousands will die.
你希望我们也被杀吗?
Do you want us to get caught up in that?
我们的任务是出去传教 不是打仗
Our job is to go out and preach, not fight.
彼得?
Peter?
彼得 那些罗马人...
Peter, the Romans...
你了解他们的为人
You know what they're like.
你清楚他们会干出什么事
You know what they'll do.
多马是对的...
Thomas is right...
这不是我们的战争
This is not our fight.
但如果我们离开这里 抛弃耶稣称为
But if we walk away and abandon the building
他父之家的神殿...
that Jesus called his father's house...
如果不试着阻止千万人死去...
if we do not try to stop thousands from dying...
如果我们袖手旁观
if we do nothing,
我们岂不是和耶稣说过的祭司们一样了吗...
are we not just like the priest that Jesus told us about...
和那些走在路的对面
The one that walked on the other side of the road
不见周围被强盗袭击的人一样?
and ignored the man who'd been attacked by robbers?
我们必须有所行动
So we have to act.
我们必须出力帮忙
We have to help.
尽我们所能
In any way we can.
那我们走吧
Then let's go.
那些 给我看看
Those ones. Let me see.
我收到煞买和希列学派的消息
I've heard from the schools of Shammai and Hillel.
他们都将与您统一战线
They will all stand with you.
时候也差不多了
It's nearly time.
在您去之前 我...
Before you go, I...
我想跟您谈谈您的妻子
I need to talk to you about your wife.
准备好了吗?
Are you ready?
是的 巡抚
Yes, Governor.
你人手够吗? 他们都清楚自己的使命吗?
You have enough men? They understand their duties?
是的
They do.
这事我不放心交给其他人
I would not trust this to any other man.
怎么了?
What's the matter?
没什么
Nothing.
他们都是好人
They're good men.
这座城市...
This city...
今日得好好教训一场
must be taught a lesson today.
如有人试图阻拦 格杀勿论
If the crowd tries to impede your progress, kill them all.
来了
It's coming.
退后! 闪开! 退开!
Stand back! Move aside! Stand aside!
快点退开! 闪开!
Stand aside! Move aside!
退开! 闹也没用!
Stand aside! You cannot win this!
别来送死!
Do not be the first to die!
退后! 赶紧退后!
Back! Stand back!
退后! 闪开!
Stand back! Stand aside!
准备! 拉!
Go! Pull!
拉紧绳子! 拉紧绳子!
Hold your lines! Hold your line!
拉紧!
Hold!
使劲! 拉!
Come on! Pull it!
让开 大祭司
Stand aside, High Priest.
我也是奉命行事
I have my orders.
请您让开
Now please stand aside.
那就来吧 百夫长
Do what you have to, centurion.
你可以一拳将我打死
You can kill me with a single blow,
但会不断有人接替我
but I will instantly be replaced,
一个接着一个
and so will the next man, and the next.
就算是你也没法杀掉耶路撒冷所有人
Even you cannot murder everyone in Jerusalem.
快! 快! 快!
Now! Now! Now!
我们在天上的父 愿人都尊你的名为圣
Our father in heaven, hallowed be your name.
愿你的国降临 愿你的旨意...
Your kingdom come, your will be done...
我的性命在狮子中间...
I dwell amongst lions...
- 行在地上 如同行在天上...  - 我躺卧在性如烈火的世人当中...
- on earth as it is in heaven...  - Forced to live amidst ravenous beasts...
我们日用的饮食 今日赐给我们 免我们的债...
Give us today our daily bread, and forgive us our trespasses...
他们的牙齿是枪 箭...
men whose teeth are Spears and arrows...
如同我们免了人的债...
as we forgive those who trespass against us...
- 神啊 愿你崇高 过于诸天...  - 不叫我们遇见试探
- Be exalted, O Lord, above the heavens...  - And lead us not into temptation,
- 救我们脱离凶恶  - 愿你的荣耀 高过全地
- but deliver us from evil.  - And may your glory descend...
我们在天上的父 愿人都尊你的名为圣
Our father in heaven, hallowed be your name.
愿你的国降临 愿你的旨意
Your kingdom come, your will be done,
行在地上 如同行在天上
on earth as it is in heaven.
我的性命在狮子中间 我躺卧在性如烈火的世人当中
I dwell amongst lions, forced to live amidst ravenous beasts,
他们的牙齿是枪 箭...
men whose teeth are Spears and arrows...
如同我们免了人的债
as we forgive those who trespass against us.
不叫我们遇见试探 救我们脱离凶恶
And lead us not into temptation but deliver us from evil.
他们的牙齿是枪 箭...
Men whose teeth are Spears and arrows...
我的性命在狮子中间 我躺卧在性如烈火的世人当中...
I dwell amongst lions, forced to live amidst ravenous beasts...
不叫我们遇见试探 救我们脱离凶恶
And lead us not into temptation but deliver us from evil.
我们日用的饮食 今日赐给我们 免我们的债...
Give us today our daily bread, and forgive us our trespasses...
退后!
Stay back!
如同我们免了人的债...
as we forgive those who trespass against us...
不叫我们遇见试探
and lead us not into temptation,
救我们脱离凶恶
but deliver us from evil.
大人 现在该怎么办?
What now, sir?
对不起
I'm sorry.
突然人群暴动
There was a sudden rush.
当然我们把他们都杀了 但是...
We killed them all, of course, but...
我们没保护好雕像
We couldn't save the statue.
百夫长 我们尽力了
We did try, centurion.
我知道
I'm sure.
如果我们必须为此受死...
If we must fall on our swords for our failures...
今天不能再有牺牲了
There will be no more death today.
召集士兵将雕像运回大殿
Get the men and the statue back to the palace.
是的 大人 马上去办
Yes, sir. Right away.
您受伤了吗?
Are you hurt?
我? 没有 怎么了?
Me? No. Why?
我以为您被砍倒了
I thought I saw you fall.
去做你的事
You have your orders.
大人
Sir.
士兵集合!
Soldiers, regroup!
走吧
Come.
你是对的
You were right.
预言在今日没有实现
The prophecy would not be fulfilled today.
神殿也保住了
And the temple is saved.
但耶稣呢?
But what about Jesus?
我以为就是今天
I thought this was it.
我以为能再次见到他了...
I thought I would see him again...
就在今日 此刻
Today, now.
你们刚才看到百夫长了吗?
Did you see the centurion?
他没有参与战斗
He didn't fight.
难道你们都没看到?
Did none of you see him?
他跪下了
He knelt.
他跪在了你面前 彼得
He knelt before you, Peter.
百夫长?
A centurion?
他为什么要这么做?
Why would he do such a thing?
因为我给他施洗了
Because I baptized him.
什么?
You did what?
大帝会再送来雕像...
He'll send another...
一个不成再来一个
and then another.
真没想到这么没完没了
I can't believe it's not over.
你怎么想?
What do you think?
你在乎吗?
What do you care?
下次我会加派人手
I'll bring in more men next time.
上午就钉死四十个女人
I'll crucify 40 women in the morning
让他们乖乖待在家里...
to keep them in their houses...
上街的就处死
Kill anyone who's seen on the streets.
不信他们不听话
That'll do the trick.
我要跟哥尼流谈一下
I need to speak with Cornelius.
我们可以赢的
We can win this.
只要再狠一点
I just need to be tougher with them.
你的计划真恶心
Your plans disgust me.
身居此位就是如此
They come with the job.
你让我憎恶
I loathe you.
我要召见大祭司和他妻子...
I need to see the High Priest and his wife...
震慑住他们
Face them down.
你去给他们安排点好吃好喝的
You will organize food and drink
粉饰下气氛 懂吗?
to mask any unpleasantness, yes?
你没听见我说的吗?
Are you not listening?
我一刻也不想跟你呆在一起
I cannot bear to be one more moment in your presence.
那你要去哪里?
Where would you go?
一个你永远找不到我的地方
Somewhere you could never find me.
你看过我是怎么对待敌人的
You've seen how I deal with my enemies.
你觉得我不会也如此为你奋力而战吗?
You don't think I would fight as hard for you?
这么残忍的事你说得可真浪漫
You almost make it sound romantic.
你清楚我的为人...
You know who I am...
也清楚我的职责
and what I am.
我们是绑在一起的
And we are bound together.
那我就割断纽带
Then I cut our ties.
一刀两断
I slash them apart.
我们永不再见
You will never see me again.
回来
Come back.
不
No.
回来
Come back.
我可以见他了吗?
Is he ready for me?
什么?
What?
巡抚他召见我
The Governor. He summoned me.
我... 我想是吧
I... I suppose.
不能让他一直等我
I shouldn't keep him waiting.
你杀了多少人?
How many did you kill?
一个都没杀
I killed no one.
我弃岗了
I abandoned my post.
我不知道自己是怎么活下来的
I don't know how I'm still alive.
你没有参战? 有人看到吗?
You didn't fight? Did anyone see?
可能有
Possibly.
那么...
Then...
要是我丈夫知道了...
If my husband learns the truth...
我会以叛国罪处死
I'll be executed as a traitor.
我们逃走吧
We can run.
我有钱...
I have money...
足够保我们平安
money enough to buy us protection.
我们去哪儿?
Where would we go?
去... 去天涯海角
To... to the ends of the earth.
你真想让我离开他吗?
You really want me to leave him?
当然
Of course.
你一点都不开心
You're so unhappy.
你想让我为了你离开他?
You want me to leave him for you?
为了耶稣
For Jesus.
我的妻儿都收拾好准备上路了
My wife and children are packed and ready to leave.
我们去找彼得或其他使徒给你施洗
We'll find Peter and the other apostles and have you baptized.
你会得到幸福
You'll find such happiness.
只要我们心中有他 在哪都无关紧要
It doesn't matter where we live once we have him in our hearts.
克劳迪娅?
Claudia?
我是个傻瓜
I'm a fool.
我真傻
I'm such a fool.
这个决定确实很重大又很冒险 但是...
It is a big decision, and one fraught with danger, but...
我是犹太巡抚的妻子
I am the wife of the Governor of Judea.
我怎么可以?
How can I?
任何人都不会被拒之门外
No one will be turned away.
我罪孽深重 他们还是接受了我
For all my sins, they took me in.
你不明白
You don't understand.
你可以获得自由
You can be free.
我不能
I cannot.
克劳迪娅!
Claudia!
他在叫我
He calls.
我该走了
I must go.
神来找我
God came to me.
我当时迟疑了 不确定他的意思
I was hesitant, not sure of his meaning.
那可是罗马人!
A Roman!
我心里也满是疑惑
I was doubtful too.
我知道这事感觉很奇怪
And I know how strange it may seem.
你!
You!
你...
You...
你现在马上跟我走
You'll come with me now.